<resources>
    <string name="all_name">all</string>
    <string name="app_name">CyberAware</string>
    <string name="blank_name">"You left your username blank"</string>
    <string name="clear_choices">RESET</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete Item?</string>
    <string name="delete_warning">Would you like to delete the selected article from Favorites?</string>
    <string name="done">Done</string>
    <string name="edit_feed">Edit Feed</string>
    <string name="enter_username">Enter Username</string>
    <string name="Erase_History">Erase History</string>
    <string name="favorite">Favorites</string>
    <string name="latitude">Latitude</string>
    <string name="location">Location:</string>
    <string name="location_message">Welcome to Cramer!</string>
    <string name="location_prompt">"use location services?"</string>
    <string name="malicious_app_instruct">*Please uninstall the following apps for your protection:</string>
    <string name="malicious_app_tag">Malicious Apps Detected:</string>
    <string name="malicious_app_warning">Malicious Apps Detected</string>
    <string name="my_feed">My Feed</string>
    <string name="news">News</string>
    <string name="no">no</string>
    <string name="notification_caps">NOTIFICATIONS</string>
    <string name="notification_name">Notifications</string>
    <string name="old_settings">Use Old Settings</string>
    <string name="personal_caps">PERSONAL</string>
    <string name="personal_filter">Personal Filter</string>
    <string name="privacy_caps">PRIVACY</string>
    <string name="recommendation_title">Recommended Article</string>
    <string name="role_instructions">Please select your skill level.</string>
    <string name="safety">Cyber Safety</string>
    <string name="save">SAVE</string>
    <string name="saved">saved</string>
    <string name="search_name">Search</string>
    <string name="settings_name">Settings</string>
    <string name="sign_up_name">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="skill_clarification">*skill level refers to how knowledgeable you are about cybersecurity*</string>
    <string name="social_media">Social Media Access</string>
    <string name="sort_name">sort</string>
    <string name="tip_name">Tips</string>
    <string name="topic_pick">Pick cybersecurity topics you are interested in:</string>
    <string name="url_toast">"URL not found"</string>
    <string name="usage">Usage:</string>
    <string name="usage_prompt">"Usage permissions must be enabled in settings for full functionality"</string>
    <string name ="usage_tag">App Usage Statistics:</string>
    <string name="username">Username</string>
    <string name="username_hint">Please enter username</string>
    <string name="whitelist">Wifi Whitelist:</string>
    <string name="wifi">Wifi:</string>
    <string name="wifi_warning">Insecure Wifi</string>
    <string name="yes">yes</string>

    <string name="malicious_app_explanation">
        \nBEWARE: We found a known malicious app on your device. Please look at the list of apps
        below and delete the corresponding app(s) from your device:
    </string>

    <string name="malicious_app_extended">
        \nNote: These apps are not in the Play Store anymore
    </string>

    <string name="usageInfo">
        *Note: To fully enable Usage, please also make sure to grant Usage Access permission in
        your Phone Settings*
    </string>

    <string name="wifi_explanation">
        \nWARNING: You are on an unencrypted and therefore insecure Wi-Fi network. Avoid logging
        into online accounts since your usernames and passwords can be easily stolen.
    </string>

    <string name="Beginner">Beginner</string>
    <string name="Intermediate">Intermediate</string>
    <string name="Advanced">Advanced</string>
    <string name="Expert">Expert</string>

    <string-array name = "user_filter_types">
        <item>Beginner</item>
        <item>Intermediate</item>
        <item>Advanced</item>
        <item>Expert</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="article_types">
        <item>Attacks</item>
        <item>Breaches</item>
        <item>Cryptography</item>
        <item>CryptoCurrency</item>
        <item>Data Breaches</item>
        <item>Decryption</item>
        <item>Encryption</item>
        <item>Internal Threats</item>
        <item>Internet of Things</item>
        <item>Malware</item>
        <item>Mobile Security</item>
        <item>Online Safety</item>
        <item>Phishing</item>
        <item>Physical Security</item>
        <item>Privacy</item>
        <item>Threats</item>
        <item>Vulnerabilities</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="tip_names">
        <item>Password Creation</item>
        <item>Password Management</item>
        <item>2-Factor Authentication</item>
        <item>Security Questions</item>
        <item>Http vs Https</item>
        <item>Phishing</item>
        <item>Check Your Wifi Connection</item>
    </string-array>

    <!--
        Keep in mind that when typing strings, inserting apostrophe's and quotation marks will
        require a preceding backslash. For example, [ you're ] needs to be [ you\'re ]. Or,
        [ he said "hello" ] needs to be [ he said \"hello\" ]
    -->

    <string-array name="tip_content">
        <item>
            Passwords should be more than the minimum amount allowed by any service and should
            include non-alphabetic characters.\n

            \nLet us look at different password combinations to get a better idea of why. Say a
            password only uses lowercase alphabetic characters and is n characters long. This means
            there are 26^n possible combinations that it could be. For example, if a password\'s
            length is eight characters, then there are 26^8 possible combinations it could be,
            which, for visualization, is equal to 208,827,064,576 different combinations. This may
            seem like a large number, but the average laptop can make 1,000,000,000 guesses per
            second, meaning it would take about 3.5 minutes to crack.\n

            \nA complex password using upper and lowercase alphabets, numbers, and special
            characters (such as %,$,#,@,!,~,^,*) is much harder to break. Since there are 95
            different characters we can use (52 characters from using the lower and uppercase
            characters of the alphabet, 10 numbers, and 33 special characters), there are 95^n
            possible permutations of the password. Now, an eight-character, complex password would
            take about 77 days to crack. Furthermore, a ten-character, complex password would take
            about 1,900 years to crack!\n

            \nNeedless to say, passwords only get stronger the longer and more complex they are.
            Therefore, it is important to make your passwords long and strong!\n

            \nThe above scenarios we used were ones where a laptop was merely guessing all the
            possible combinations that a password could be. This is called a \'brute force\' attack.
            However, there are many other ways that your passwords can be cracked. For example, say
            you have a long password that has uppercase, lowercase, numeric, and special characters.
            For our example, say your password is Password123!. Despite meeting all the requirements
            of being long and complex, this password will actually be easily cracked. Why? Because
            this password is a common password.\n

            \nCommon passwords can be cracked using a Dictionary attack. A Dictionary attack is a
            form of a brute force attack. The difference is that Dictionary attacks narrow the
            guessing threshold to a pre-made wordlist of common and/or compromised passwords.\n

            \nA danger of wordlists is that there are many circulating around. For example, there is
            a famous wordlist called \'Rockyou\' that was obtained in 2009 when a company
            experienced a database breach that resulted in millions of user data being compromised.
            User passwords were not encrypted in the company\'s database, meaning that the plaintext
            passwords were easily stolen. As a result, the infamous \'Rockyou\' wordlist containing
            around 14.3 million unique passwords was created. The moral of the story is that even if
            passwords are long and use complex characters, if the password is common or easy to
            guess, then it can still be easily cracked.\n

            \nTherefore, please keep in mind three things when creating a password:\n
                \t**Length: make it more than the minimum required length\n
                \t**Complexity: use a combination of cased alphanumeric, special characters\n
                \t**Commonality: do not use common phrases/words in your passwords\n
        </item>

        <item>
            As we covered in our tips about Password Creation, it is important that passwords be
            long, complex, and not contain common words/phrases. For this section, we will cover the
            importance of password uniqueness and the helpfulness of password managers.\n

            \nTo begin, for each service (e.g., social media, online store, etc.) you use, the
            password you create for each service should be unique. Many password creations result in
            a user reusing a password he or she previously created. Similarly, many password changes
            oftentimes result in a password being changed to a slight variation of the original
            password. This can be predictable and make passwords easier to crack if the hacker is
            able to obtain the old password from a compromised database. Imagine if one of your
            passwords is lost in a data breach. If you use similar passwords, then it will be easier
            to guess what your other passwords might be. Worse yet, if you use the same password,
            then all your other accounts are compromised! Yikes!\n

            \nAt this point, you may be thinking that remembering each password you create would be
            impossible, but this is where password managers come in. Password managers are trusty,
            reliable tools that can store all your usernames and passwords and help keep them safe.
            Furthermore, for online services, password managers can help you automatically log in to
            your account. Therefore, you only need to remember one password—the password for your
            password manager.\n
            *Just remember to make sure the password you create for your password manager is long
            and complex so that it is extremely difficult if not near impossible to break into your
            password manager.*\n

            \nAs a last note, when selecting a password manager, make sure the password manager you
            are using is legitimate by checking the reputation of the company that produced the
            password manager. Other things to check are the reviews and downloads to see if other
            people are using and enjoying the service. Best of luck!\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Two-factor authentication offers an extra layer of protection for your accounts. When
            logging into an account, after you enter your username and corresponding password, you
            typically obtain access to your account. However, with two-factor authentication, even
            after entering the correct username and password, you must offer a second method of
            authentication.\n

            \nThe second method of authentication can be divided into three categories:\n
	            \t*Something you know\n
	            \t*Something you have\n
	            \t*Something you are\n

            \nSomething you know, as the name suggests, asks for information from you. These can
            take the form of entering a pin or answering a security question.\n

            \nSomething you have requires having a physical token with you, such as a credit card or
            a cellphone.\n

            \nSomething you are asks for biometric verification, such as a fingerprint, face scan,
            or iris scan.\n

            \nYou\'ve likely had experience using two-factor authentication before. For example, if
            you\'ve gone to an ATM to withdraw some cash, then you\'ve likely used two-factor
            authentication. More specifically, the authentication you\'ve used likely fell into the
            \'something you know\' and \'something you have\' categories: your pin for something you
            know and your card for something you have.\n

            \nTwo common methods of two-factor authentication are text-message and app-based
            authentication, both falling under the category of \'something you have.\'\n

            \nText-message authentication requires using your cellphone. In this case, a code will
            be texted to you.\n

            \nApp-based authentication also requires your cellphone. You will need to download a
            free app that generates a new code every thirty seconds. When trying to log in, you will
            need to type in the current code displayed on the app.\n

            \nText-message and app-based authentication both use time-sensitive codes. In other
            words, the codes sent or displayed are meant to be used only once and expire after a
            given time limit. As a result, even if a hacker obtained your login credentials, unless
            they had access to your second authentication method, it would be exceedingly difficult
            for him or her to hack into your account.\n

            \nIf a website, app, or other account type offers two-factor authentication, it is
            recommended that you set it up. This way, you have a better chance of protecting
            yourself against hackers. Remember, if you see an attempt to hack into your account that
            failed because of two-factor authentication, you\'ll be thankful!\n
        </item>

        <item>
            It is important when creating/selecting security questions that they are easy for you to
            remember, but not easy enough for a potential hacker to guess. Security questions used
            to be more secure, but with the creation of social media, it is much easier to obtain
            the answers to common security questions (such as your pet\'s name, favorite color,
            street you grew up on, childhood friend\'s name, etc.).\n

            \nTherefore, when creating/selecting security questions, try to make sure it is not
            something a person can determine by looking through your social media accounts or by
            simply knowing you well.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            When entering login information or any personal data online, it is important to check
            your browser to make sure the web connection is secure. Most browsers now have the
            built-in lock icon on the address bar to notify you when the browser has been certified
            as a secure connection. If you see that the lock icon is unlocked or broken, it means
            that your connection is insecure.\n

            \nBesides looking for the lock icon, another way to check whether your connection is
            secure is to check the web address. If the web address has \"http\" instead of
            \"https,\" then it is an insecure connection.\n

            \nHTTP stands for Hypertext Transfer Protocol and is the protocol used when
            communicating/transferring data via the internet. The difference between HTTP and HTTPS
            is that the \"S\" in HTTPS stands for \"Secure.\" In other words, HTTPS is a secure
            version of HTTP, where HTTPS encrypts the information exchanged between a user and web
            server—something HTTP neglects to do. If you find yourself on an http website, that
            means you are vulnerable to what is known as a Man in the Middle attack.\n

            \nA Man in the Middle attack is an attack where a perpetrator intercepts and/or
            manipulates communication between a user and a web application. For example, if you log
            in to an insecure online service, a hacker could intercept the unencrypted login
            information that you send to the web server and thereby steal your login credentials.
            Another example is that the hacker could alter messages/content that the web server
            sends you and trick you into thinking you are interacting with the website. However, in
            reality, you would be interacting with the hacker!\n

            \nSo, when you are browsing the internet, make sure your connection is secure. Check
            that the lock icon is displayed on your browser and that you are on an https website.
            Hackers always get the upper hand if users are in a hurry and/or not paying attention.
            Therefore, to counter that, remember to always be alert for a safer online experience!\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Phishing attacks occur when a scammer tries to get a user to hand over personal
            information by disguising him/herself as a trusted entity. Forms of phishing include
            fraudulent calls, emails, ads, and texts.\n

            \nCalls and texts from unknown numbers can be suspicious. If you receive a call or text
            from an unknown number claiming to be a person, company, or government agency
            (such as the IRS) and they ask for sensitive, personal information, then it is highly
            likely that the call or text is a phishing scam.\n

            \nFraudulent emails, unlike fraudulent calls and texts, are usually much harder to spot.
            With our growing technology, phishing emails are getting more and more sophisticated.
            However, there are some clues and tips to keep in mind which you can use to help protect
            yourself.\n

            \nFirst, similar to a call or text scam, look at the email\'s sender and determine
            whether you know them or the company they claim to be affiliated with. If you do not,
            then it\'s likely a scam.\n

            \nSecond, if you do know the person or company, check to see if the address matches your
            organization and/or matches past emails from who they claim to be. If it does not match,
            it is likely a scam and you should alert the person or organization.\n

            \nIf the email address seems legitimate, there are other clues you can look out for. For
            example, look at the quality of the email. If there are multiple spelling errors, then
            it is a sign of unprofessionalism and lets you know that it is a poorly crafted email—a
            sign of a cheap fraud.\n

            \nYou can also look for unusually generic formatting. For example, let\'s say you
            receive an email from a company (such as Amazon, Microsoft, Netflix, etc.) asking you to
            update your payment information. However, upon closer inspection, you notice that it
            does not specify your username, name, or anything personal to your account. If that is
            the case, then it is likely a scam. If the company needed you to do something with your
            account, it will have your information on-hand and will send a somewhat personalized
            message (such as saying \"Dear YourName\" instead of \"Dear customer\"). One last clue
            to look out for is checking to see if the email is asking you to do an unusual task.
            If it is, then it might be a scam.\n

            \nIf you are unsure and/or feel suspicious about an email, contact the person or company
            directly. When you contact the person or company, do not simply hit \"reply\" to the
            email as it will alert the potential scammer. Instead, open a new email and in the
            sender\'s email address, enter an email address you know to be correct.\n

            \n*In any case, if the email looks or feels suspicious, do not click on any links or
            attachments that are provided in the email as they may contain malware. Even if you
            trust the email\'s sender, always be alert if you click on a link that redirects you to
            a webpage. Always check that the web address is correct and that your connection to the
            web page is secure (read \"http vs https\" in our tips)*\n

            \nLastly, be cautious of online ads. Clicking on an ad usually results in being
            redirected to a webpage so that a user can purchase the item or service being
            advertised. This can be dangerous as there are many fraudulent internet sites. However,
            if you do decide to click an ad, check to make sure the website you are being redirected
            to is a legitimate site (such as checking to see if you are on a legitimate Amazon
            website) and that your connection is secure (read \"http vs https\" in our tips). Always
            remember to not enter any personal information to an insecure and/or untrusted site and
            to try to keep ad-clicking to a minimum.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            \nBe cautious when connecting to a new Wi-Fi network; make sure the network is secure.
            Secure networks, such as personal home networks and trusted school networks, are
            normally encrypted. However, open or public networks are normally unencrypted.
            Consequently, connecting to an open network leaves you vulnerable to your network
            traffic (the data transmitted between your device and server) being monitored.
            Therefore, whenever you are on a public network (e.g., airport, café, restaurant, hotel,
            etc.), avoid logging into/entering personal information online as it can be seen through
            unencrypted web traffic.\n

            \nEncrypted Wi-Fi networks typically offer more security. Today, there are two types of
            Wi-Fi encryptions: WEP (Wired Equivalent Privacy) and WPA (Wi-Fi Protected Access). To
            check if the network you are on uses a form of WEP or WPA encryption, you can go to the
            Wi-Fi section of this app.\n
            *To access the Wi-Fi section, go to the News page and tap the Wi-Fi icon; it will let
            you know whether your network is encrypted.*\n

            \nTo manually check whether your network is encrypted on Windows and Android, go to the
            list of available Wi-Fi\'s on your device. Click the network you are on and select
            \"Properties\" or \"Settings.\"\n

            \nWhen looking for Wi-Fi networks, also make sure the network you are connecting to is
            the correct network you want to connect to and not a fake network with a similar name.
            There have been instances where networks have been set up with similar names to other
            networks to trick users into giving login credentials.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
